Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
Lucky!
I'm so lucky that I can go shopping
with you today, Mr. Kaji!
What?! Isn't this the swimsuit section?
Please allow us to announce
a call for a customer.
Hey! Hey! How do you like this?
Mr. Yamazaki from lbaragi City,
your friend is waiting for you.
Slow down, school girl.
Aren't you a little young for that?
Please come to Customer Service
on the first floor.
You're just so behind the times, Mr. Kaji.
This is pretty normal nowadays.
Really? I had no idea.
But this is the big school trip.
You've got to go all out!
Travel Pamphlet
Public Middle School 1
And where are you going for the trip?
Activity Destinations
Day 1 - Depart from New Tokyo-3 International Airport to Okinawa (New Kadena, Main Island)
Day 2 - Main Island to Kerama Islands to Miyako Island
Day 3 - Miyako Island to Arrive at New Tokyo-3 International Airport
Okinawa!
We're even scheduled to go scuba diving!
Schedule
Day 2
Wake up
Breakfast
(buffet)
Scuba Diving
(first time)
Lunch
(boxed)
Scuba Diving
(second time)
Scuba diving...
Come to think of it, it's been
three years since I've gone diving.
Say, where did you go for your school trip?
Oh, we didn't have one.
Why not?
Because of the Second Impact.
EPISODE 10
MAGMA DIVER
I can't go on the trip?!
Right.
Why not?!
Because you're on standby for combat duty.
You never told me anything about that!
I just told you.
Who in the hell decided that?!
Me, the Operations Planning Manager.
Hey, why don't you stop slurping that tea
and say something!
You're a man, aren't you?
Actually, I kind of anticipated
it would be like this.
And you've already given up?
How pathetic. Nothing's more useless
than a housebroken male.
Please don't talk about me like that.
I know how you must feel,
but there's just no helping this.
There's always the possibility of
an Angel attack while you're gone.
It's always standby!
Standby, standby, standby!
We've always got to be ready to defend
against an enemy who may not even come!
Why don't you try to find out where they are,
and attack them for once?!
If we could do that,
we'd have already done it.
Look, think of this as a good opportunity.
While the rest of your class is on the trip,
the two of you can study a little.
Or do you think I don't know about these?
You're greatly mistaken if you thought
I wouldn't find out about these.
What you get on your tests at school
is piped directly to me.
It's ridiculous. Who cares about grades?
I've got absolutely no interest in
the old-fashioned grading system.
When in Rome, do as the Romans do.
Try to adjust to Japanese school life.
No way!
Asuka, I'll bring you some souvenirs!
Well, it's just too bad for you guys!
I'll have enough fun for both of ya!
Paste the observation data on Mt. Asama
from Balthasar to Melchior
as soon as possible.
A school trip?
That's pretty carefree for times like these.
Well, it's because the times are so hard
that they want to have a little fun
while they can.
What are you up to?
Studying science.
You're such a diligent student.
You can say that, but I have to do it anyway.
Ta da!
Since I can't go scuba diving in Okinawa,
I'm going to do it here!
Really?
Let's see. What're you working on?
Let me take a look.
You can't solve an easy equation like this?
There, done.
It's so easy.
How can you solve a difficult
problem like this,
and not make good grades on your tests?
Because I couldn't figure out
what the questions said.
You mean you couldn't read
the questions in Japanese?
Right, I haven't learned all
the Chinese characters yet.
We didn't study it in college over there.
College?
Oh, I graduated last year.
So, what does this one say?
It's about thermal expansion.
Thermal expansion? That's kid stuff!
To put it simply,
things expand when they get hot,
and shrink when they get cold.
Well, yeah, but...
If I were to warm up just my breasts,
do you think they'd grow a little bigger?
I wouldn't know anything about that!
What a boring guy.
Watch this, Shinji!
Back roll entry!
This just isn't clear enough.
But just as the report from Mt. Asama
Earthquake Research Laboratory says,
this shadow is definitely suspicious.
Of course, we can't ignore this.
What is the Magi's judgment?
Fifty-fifty.
Is someone there yet?
Captain Katsuragi's already on site.
You're too deep!
Not yet. Another 500, please.
Depth 1200. The pressure resistant
partition is cracking.
Ms. Katsuragi!
If it breaks, we'll pay for the damage.
200 more.
We're monitoring a reaction!
Begin analysis!
Yes, Ma'am!
The probe has imploded due
to the extreme pressure.
What about the analysis?
Just barely made it. The pattern is blue.
There's no doubt, it's an Angel.
As of now, this laboratory will be
completely sealed off!
It's under Nerv's jurisdiction now!
Any and all access to the outside
world is prohibited,
and all records of the events of the
past six hours are classified.
Seismic Wave Analysis Room 2
Seismic Wave Analysis Room 1
Request an A-17 from Commander lkari,
top priority!
Watch what you're saying.
This is an open line.
I know. Hurry up and switch
to a scrambled line.
A-17?!
We're going to launch an offensive?
Correct.
Unacceptable, it's too dangerous.
You had better not say you've forgotten
what happened fifteen years ago.
This is a chance to move from
a consistently defensive posture
to an offensive one for the first time.
The risk is too large.
However, I'm sure you're aware how
important a live Angel sample would be.
We will not tolerate failure.
Failure?
If we fail, it will result in the extinction
of the human race.
You're really sure about this?
This is an Angel?
Yes, it's something like a chrysalis
prior to reaching the adult stage.
This operation's prime objective
is to capture this Angel.
We must capture it alive, as close
to its original state as possible.
And if we can't?
Then you must destroy it immediately.
Do you understand?
Yes, Ma'am!
The designated pilot for
the actual operation is...
Hey, let me! I'll dive!
But I'll bet it's going to be me again.
Asuka.
Carry out the mission using Unit 02.
Sure! This'll be a piece of cake.
And me?
The prototype Unit 00 isn't compatible with
the special equipment we'll be using.
Rei and Unit 00 will remain at
headquarters on standby.
Yes, Ma'am.
Oh, too bad for you.
You don't get to go to the hot springs.
Since an A-17 has been ordered,
we'll scramble immediately.
Get ready.
Yes, Ma'am!
You say this is the heat resistant plug suit,
but it's not any different.
Try pressing the switch on the right.
Oh, no!
What is this?!
Unit 02 is also ready.
No! What is that?!
The suit is designed to protect you from
heat, pressure, and radiation.
This is Type-D equipment, for combat
under extreme environmental duress.
Is that my Unit 02?
No way! Count me out!
I don't want to appear in public in this!
This sort of thing is up Shinji's alley!
That's too bad.
I was anticipating seeing Asuka's
gallant figure!
No!
But I don't have the courage to go
in front of Mr. Kaji looking so uncool!
This is a problem.
Yes...
Excuse me, but I...
I'll go in Unit 02.
Sorry, but I don't want you
touching my Unit 02!
I'd rather do it than let
the First take my place.
I know it's uncool, but put up with it, okay?
Eva Units 01 and 02 have arrived.
Have both units stand by in position.
Move in the laser bore, and ready the crane.
Roger.
Boom arm fixed in place.
Coolant circulation system going on auto.
Hey, where's Mr. Kaji?
That jerk won't be here.
There's nothing for him to do.
Damn! I wanted him to see how great I am.
So, an A-17 has been ordered.
That includes the freeze of all current assets.
I'm sure there are many people who
will be put out by that.
Why didn't you stop them?
I didn't have any excuse.
The order was official.
But if Nerv fails, it'll mean
the end of the world.
They're not that arrogant.
What are those?
The UN's Air Force is on standby alert.
Until this mission has been completed.
Are they going to help us?
No, they're here to clean up.
In case we fail.
What do you mean?
They will use N2 depth charges to
destroy the Angel, and us with it.
That's awful!
Who would order something like that?
Commander Ikari.
Laser operation, complete.
The bore path has been secured.
The Type D equipment
is functioning normally.
Unit 02 is in position to dispatch.
Roger.
Asuka, are you ready?
Anytime you are.
Launch!
Looks hot!
Unit 02 is entering the lava.
Watch this, Shinji!
Giant stroke entry!
Current depth, 170. Speed of descent, 20.
No problems detected.
Visibility is zero. I can't see a thing.
Switching to CT monitor.
Even with this, visibility is no more than 120.
Depth, 400...
450...
500...
550...
600...
650...
900...
950...
1000...
1020...
We're over the maximum safe depth.
Depth is 1300. Estimated target level.
Asuka, can you see anything?
No reactions detected. It's not here.
It seems the lava current
is faster than we thought.
The target's velocity doesn't
match our predictions.
Hurry up and re-calculate.
Continue the operation. Resume descent.
Depth, 1350...
1400...
A crack has occurred in
the second coolant pipe.
Depth, 1480...
We're over the maximum allowed depth.
We haven't made contact with the target yet.
Keep going.
How's it going, Asuka?
Looks like we're still good. I just want to
hurry up, finish this, and take a shower.
There's a nice hot spring near here.
We'll hit it once we're done.
Hang in there a little longer.
Maximum allowed depth plus 120.
Eva Unit 02 has lost its prog knife.
Maximum allowed depth plus 200.
Miss Katsuragi, any more than this and...
There's a human on board this time!
I am in charge of this operation.
Proceed, please.
Misato's right. I'm okay. I can keep going.
Depth, 1780...
We've reached the adjusted target depth.
There it is!
Visual confirmation of the target.
Prepare to capture.
Both of you are being moved
by convection currents,
so you'll only have one chance
to make contact.
I know. Leave it to me.
T-minus 30 to contact.
Relative velocity 2.2. I'm now on the axis.
Electromagnetic cage deployed.
No problems detected.
The target has been captured.
Nice one, Asuka.
Capture operation completed.
I'm coming up now.
Are you all right, Asuka?
Of course! Fear is often worse
than the danger, as they say.
It really was a piece of cake.
But this is more of a sauna suit
than a plug suit.
I can't wait to get to the hot spring.
Looks like the tension let loose all at once.
You think?
You were scared about this operation too,
weren't you?
Well, yeah, because if we handled it badly,
we'd have had a repeat performance.
That's true, the Second Impact.
We don't need another of those.
What's going on?!
Not good! It's started to emerge!
It's much earlier than we predicted!
Status of the cage?!
No way it can hold!
Abort the capture! Jettison the cage!
We're changing the operation!
Destroying the Angel is now top priority!
Unit 02, prepare for combat as you withdraw!
What I've been waiting for!
Damn, I forgot I dropped the knife!
It's right in front!
Releasing ballast!
It's fast!
This is bad. I've lost sight of it.
In addition to that, I've got lousy visibility,
I'm really hot,
and this suit's plastered to me
and feels disgusting.
This really sucks.
Asuka!
We'll take this chance to drop you
Unit 01's knife. Catch it!
Roger!
Oh, no! Have you dropped it yet, Shinji?
Contact with knife, 40 seconds.
The Angel is approaching rapidly!
No! Go away!
Hurry up with it!
Come on, it's too slow!
Oh, no!
Unbelievable! How could it open its mouth
in such an environment?
Its construction must be incredible!
Left leg damaged!
Engage heat shields!
Damn you!
If it can withstand such a high heat,
high pressure environment,
then the prog knife will be useless against it!
Then what should we do?
I know!
Just like earlier!
Eat this!
I see! Thermal expansion!
Transfer all coolant pressure
to cable three! Hurry!
Right when I succeeded...
Oh, man, is this it?
Shinji?
Idiot, don't go overboard.
Oomiya
Hello?
Welcome
Nerv
Party
Is there anyone from Nerv here?
Yes!
I need your signature here.
Thanks so much.
From Mr. Kaji?
What could it be?
The bath is over there, to the left.
Heavenly!
I never knew a bath could feel this good.
Shinji, can you hear me?
Yes, Ma'am!
Would you throw me the body shampoo?
We ran out of ours.
Here it comes.
Roger.
Ouch!
You idiot! Watch where you're throwing!
You suck!
Sorry.
Don't hit me in some weird spot.
Let me take a look.
Wow, your skin is so soft and smooth, Asuka!
Don't! You're tickling me!
How about right here?
Don't touch that!
Come on, it doesn't wear out!
It expanded.
How embarrassing!
Oh, this? I got this in the Second Impact.
You know all about my past, don't you?
Well, yeah. It's part of my job.
It's all ancient history for both of us.
We shouldn't let it bother us.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
Those who don't think well of Nerv cut off
the power supply to all of New Tokyo-3.
With none of the modern facilities
operational, an Angel closes in.
Next episode: "In the Still Darkness"
IN THE STILL DARKNESS
Expect more fan service next time too!